## FREDNEL JEAN-JOSEPH

# **Full stack Web Developer**

Portfolio / GitHub / LinkedIn

# **Summary**

Entrepreneurial full-stack web developer heavily focusing on web development. My goal is to build value by maintaining and/or building projects of the highest quality to better our community and contribute to the growth of our environment. I have experience working in teams as well as without supervision as I am flexible, adaptable, and very passionate about delivering the best technical solutions.

## **Education**

**Grand Circus of Detroit - April to June 2021** 

- Fulltime/Daytime full stack C#/.NET Bootcamp
- Backend C#/Net, MVC, SQL and SSMS, Web API
- Frontend JavaScript, TypeScript/Angular, HTML/CSS/Bootstrap

East Carolina University – Spring 2018 to Summer 2019

- BSBA Management Information System
- GPA 3.775/4.00

# **Technical Skills**

#### **Frontend**

- JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax
- HTML5, JSON, CSS3, Bootstrap
- Typescript/Angular

#### **Databases**

- MS SQL Server, Entity Framework
- PL/SQL, Toad for Oracle
- SSRS, SSIS, ORM, T-SQL

### Backend

- C#/.NET, ASP.NET MVC
- Node.js, Web API

#### **SDLC**

- 12 Factor App, Agile, BRD
- OOP, SOLID Principle
- Data Structure & Algorithm

# **Experiences**

Technology & Business Solutions LLC / Software Developer – 08/2021 to Present

- Developing and adding new features, capabilities, and improvements
- Debugging, testing, and maintaining the legacy codebase
- Collaborating with other team members and brainstorming new concepts.
- Troubleshooting support issues.

mr.jeanjoseph@gmail.com (919) 590-0999

## Accenture PLC / CRM Analyst – 05/2019 to 04/2021

- Provided helpdesk support for North Carolina State Purchasing System, NC eProcurement.
- Resolved technical problems relating to business-critical customer facing portal resulting in system performance and scalability improvements.
- Diagnosed, troubleshoot, and resolved ranges of software, and connectivity issues. Excelled at probing and researching, analyzing, and rectifying problems.
- Received excellent evaluations on monthly performance reviews for teamwork, customer service, communication skills, and technical problem-solving.
- Software used to perform daily tasks include ServiceNow CRM, PowerBI, Advanced Excel, JIRA, and the continuous learning of the new software as they become necessary tools to solve customerrelated issues.

# Sprint Nextel / Lead Retail Sales Consultant – 10/2006 to 02/2017

- Delivered sales and profit growth through strategic sales practices that resulted in 31% and above sales increase month over month.
- Recruited, trained, and retained exceptional team members.
- Analyzed business strategies and processes to determine gaps and developed action plans to improve performance.
- Oversaw store operation and established daily and weekly cash reconciliation process.
- Handled customer complaints and escalations and reduced churn by 50% month over month.